# Noorah Alhasan

LBJ School of Public Affairs | The University of Texas at Austin | P.O. Box Y | Austin, TX 78713-8925 noorah.alhasan@utexas.edu | 512.998.9474

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a data scientist with over three years of experience in qualitative and quantitative methods in comparative environmental and energy policy. Passionate about data engineering and management, I have a knack for exploring unstructured data and identifying insights supporting the policy decision-making process. I am looking for opportunities to utilize my skills and knowledge to help local nonprofit organizations achieve their mission goals and objectives.

## **EDUCATION**

#### THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN | Austin, TX

Ph.D. IN PUBLIC POLICY ONGOING

Dissertation: Essays on Sustainability Transition Pathways in the Gulf Monarchies

#### MASTER IN PUBLIC AFFAIRS 2017

Policy Research Project: Education Productivity

- Texas Postsecondary and Career Counseling Initiative
  - Information, Technology, and Commercialization Strategies in U.S. Higher Education

Policy Research Project: Comparison of New Electric Utility Business Models

#### **KUWAIT UNIVERSITY** | Shuwaikh, Kuwait

M.A. IN ECONOMICS

Thesis: Public Spending and Economic Growth in the Rentier State: The Case of Kuwait

B.B.A. IN ECONOMICS 2009

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN | POLICY RESEARCHER

AUG 2017 – PRESENT

Austin. TX

- Conducted original research in the political economy of renewable energy policies in oil-rich countries using unsupervised NLP models that resulted in a white paper
- Presented original research in international renewable energy and public policy conferences (conference poster and paper session)
- Webscraped over one million news articles from Arabic-based newspapers and deployed machine learning techniques to extract and preprocess text into measurable observations
- Deployed machine learning models to analyze news trends in energy and environmental policies in oil-rich countries

#### THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN | TEACHING ASSISTANT

AUG 2018 - PRESENT

Austin, TX

- Created weekly teaching material for a group of 30 master students
- Provided more than 30 private mentoring sessions in microeconomics theories and principles at the graduate level
- Tracked and assessed the academic progress of more than 30 students in a given semester

## TEXAS COMMISSION ON ENVIRONMENTAL QUALITY

May 2016 - Aug 2016

BORDER AFFAIRS POLICY INTERN | Austin, TX

- Provided administrative and programmatic support of environmental activities along the U.S. Mexico Border for TCEQ's Border Affairs program
- Conducted research and drafting reports related to border environmental policy and participating in stakeholder meetings
- Participated in the Bi-National Green Energy Forum in San Antonio, Texas

#### INDUSTRIAL BANK OF KUWAIT | RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

Nov 2014 - Jul 2015

Kuwait City, Kuwait

• Conducted monthly and quarterly reports analyzing domestic and international trends in the manufacturing industry

#### **GULF CENTER FOR DEVELOPMENT POLICIES**

SEP 2013 - SEP 2014

RESEARCH ANALYST & EDITOR | Mishref, Kuwait

- Conducted original research for the center as part of the annual publication
- Coordinated with independent researchers and edited their papers and reports for the center
- Coordinated with the creative team on the design and layout of the annual publication
- Built a database of historical macroeconomic data on the Gulf region

## SKILLS

#### RESEARCH

Interviews • Survey design Program evaluation • Data visualization

## **PROGRAMMING**

R • Python • SQL • LATEX CSS • HTML • Markdown Git

#### **SOFTWARE**

Tableau • Excel • Rstudio Github • NVivo • ArcGIS

## **LANGUAGES**

Arabic (Native) English (Bilingual Proficiency)